<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Indigenous Futures</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string-array name="menu_array">
        <item>Home</item>
        <item>About</item>
        <item>Contributors</item>
        <item>Tours</item>
        <item>Resources</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about_text_1">
           \t For our concluding Indigenous Futures: Decolonizing NYC -- Documenting the Lenape Trail seminar project, we propose to focus our attention to a larger scale project of reestablishing collective memory of the Lenape homeland, Manahahtaan - through a collection of artwork, events, non-linear narratives, activism, interactive maps, and conversations. Upon navigating conversations that will concern not just Lenape, but indigenous futurities within the context of Manahahtaan; within the context of this group\'s varying understandings of indigenous\' realities and experiences, the crux of this project attempts to be very intersectional, collective and exploratory. Our individual and collective research take on this same approach by outlining a type of de-colonial effort that probes, meditates on, and experiments with how our identities and backgrounds motivate our collective imaginings of indigenous people\'s past, present, and future.
            \n\n
            \tWith our work paying homage to the first people of Manahahtaan Island, our collective intent is to honor their longstanding presence, contributions and history on this land. Foremost, we would like to point out that this project does not and will not serve as an authority in Lenape Cultural re-memories. Instead this project helps us carve out imaginative, artistic, and physical platforms in how we re-imagine and engage with Indigenous histories, futures, and realities as outsiders. In this sense, as both visitors on their island and outsiders to their cultural historiographies, we are continually reminded of the limitations of our work in representing and articulating lived indigenous realities. In an effort to best honor indigenous communities, our work remains under the guidance of Lenape and indigenous cultural bearers, who have helped us along the way, sifted through our queries and varying abstractions of Lenape futurities.
            \n\n
            \tAs colonial and imperialist perspectives and intentions continue to be present, we recognize the importance of aligning our work with indigenous issues and realities, which  include: Afro-Diasporic spatial relations, the New York State Pilgrim Pipeline, as well as similarly overlooked ecological/indigenous disputes surrounding Standing Rock, Mauna Kea, and the Sacramento River (Salmon run). Additionally we hope to ensure that our collective group efforts should not and will not stand as a "palatable" replacement to indigenous historiographies; rather we believe everyone should make strides in actively learning and decolonizing their approaches in re-imagining Lenape and indigenous futures.
            \n\n
            \tLastly, while our collective project continues to unfurl into an intentional educational apparatus of disruption- meant to call out and parade colonialism\'s ravenous presence on Lenape\'s historiographies and claim to futurity- we find ourselves facing various disruptions as we work through and grapple with how our individual identities and cultures could re-animate different indigenous futures. For right now viewers could witness these unfolding questions, reflections and constraints by tracking our geographic mapping and cartography of a de-colonial Lenapehoking - Manahahtaan. Each point on this map speaks to our individual and collective re-memory and understanding as it relates to Lenape and indigenous environments, waterways, plants, animals, land, mobility, and temporality. We hope this project will propel others to create more collaborative dreaming spaces that work to decolonize, re-imagine, and re-animate alternate futures for indigenous and marginalized folks.
            \n\n
            \tThanks.
    </string>
    <string name="more_info">More Information</string>
    <string name="about_text_2">
        \n\n
        \tThe "Indigenous Futures: Decolonizing NYC" class would like to thank the Lenape people on whose land we live and who inspired this project and our ongoing allyship.
        \n\n
        \tWe thank Chief Vincent Mann (Ramapough Lunaape Nation\'s Turtle Clan), Brent Stonefish (Lunaapeew Nation at Delaware Nation - Moravian of the Thames), and Paula K. Pechonick, Curtis Zunigha, and Joe Baker (Delaware Tribe of Indians) for sharing their experiences and knowledges with us as Lenape elders.
        \n\n
        \tWe thank Rick Chavolla (Kumeyaay Tribe), Kumu Pua Case, Alex Jimerson (Seneca Nation), George Reis, Jim Rementer, and Beatrice Glow for sharing their knowledge and continuing to give us feedback throughout the project\'s development.
        \n\n
        \tThanks to Jenny Kijowski, Amita Manghnani, Ruby Gomez, Laura Chen-Schultz, the Lenape Center, and NYU\'s A/P/A Institute.
        \n\n
        \tThis project was produced with funds from NYU\'s Gallatin Teaching-with-Technology Grant.
        \n\n
    </string>


    <string name="kml_google">http://googlemaps.github.io/kml-samples/morekml/Polygons/Polygons.Google_Campus.kml</string>
    <string name="kml_url">https://github.com/dl2514/dl2514.github.io/blob/master/Indigenous_Futures_Decolonizing_NYC.kml?raw=true</string>

    <string name="jane"><b>Jane</b>
    \n
    \tI\'m Jane, a junior at Gallatin studying computer science and urban planning - I\'m interested in different ways software can be used to make cities more sustainable and inclusive- places where people feel respected, happy, and safe. I love working with different kinds of technology and want to program our class website in a way that represents Lenape culture, spiritualities, and knowledges in a meaningful way. Being part of the generation that lives in the \"information age,\" we should use all the data and tools that we can access to communicate and tackle some of the ongoing issues that our society and environment are facing. I learned a valuable lesson about how to develop tech that addresses societal issues during my previous semester when I studied abroad in the United Arab Emirates and participated in the "Smart Cities for Women: Dubai" hackathon. I was part of a team that initiated a platform for giving women and expatriates a greater voice in the Dubai government. Through my experience, I realized that, understanding and listening to the stakeholders is the greatest asset in developing a successful, meaningful application. \n\n

    \tAs a Korean immigrant who gained American citizenship through her parents, I have been raised with privilege and spent most of my life not being aware of it. Learning more about Lenape history has made me uncomfortable and also grateful; I am living on Lenape grounds, and I had never recognized it before this semester. I consider my father and his business in New York quite successful; however, I also have to acknowledge that his store is not just an indicator of his hard work but an opportunity that has been given through capitalism and colonization. Children of immigrants are usually told not to forget where they are from; rarely are they asked to question the whereabouts of the native people of the land that they are residing in. Through this project, I want to encourage more families of immigrants to acknowledge this discomfort and think more about decolonizing their experiences- to think not just about their heritage but also of the history of the land that they migrated to.\n\n

    \tThe first phase of the research that I\'m doing for our project is centered around plants that the Lenape used for medicinal purposes. The question I wanted to tackle was how cultures have used both herbal remedies and pharmaceutical drugs. Growing up, whenever I got sick my mom was always quick to hand me whatever cough syrup we had in our cabinet. However, my parents also exposed me to alternative medicines and therapies such as acupuncture, cupping, and chiropractic. \n\n

    \tInspired by my exposure to these different kinds of medicines, I created a storybook connecting stories of a New York City pharmacist and a Lenape healer. The book has two "beginnings" on each side of the book, and the "endings" converge in the middle. On one end of the book, the Lenape healer, who was chosen by her community for her spiritual connection and knowledge of plants, goes on a search to find the items in need when her friend\'s baby was sick. After praying, she finds the American elderberry (sambucus canadensis), a beautiful flower that she takes back to her village and brews. On the other side of the book, the main character is a pharmacist working in one of the many Duane Reade stores in Manhattan. The pharmacist reaches for his customer\'s prescription and goes back in time to the 1970\'s and 1980\'s, where medical researchers have strived to make natural drugs but have given up because they were difficult to duplicate. These drugs have been effective, but are leading us to the end of the "pharmaceutical era," where the medicines we buy are becoming less effective. The pharmacist returns back to the present to read an article about a botanist in Georgia who has been searching for more medicinal plants to combat our use of pharmaceutical drugs.\n\n

    \tAfter my research on the relationship between herbal medicine and synthetic drugs, I looked at other plants that the Lenape utilized, and extrapolated upon that research to draw conclusions on the rights of Lenape women and the ecology of parks in New York City. \n\n</string>

    <string name="molly"><b>Molly</b>
    \n
        \tMy name is Molly Smith and I\'m a third year at NYU\'s Gallatin School. I\'m studying transnationalism, focused on problems with modern day organizations involving sovereignty, authority, and enforcement. That is, I look at how structures of global governance emerge and conduct themselves in our world. The most prominent example of this subject matter would be the current conflict surrounding Brexit, the European Union, and nationalist movements across the world. This interdisciplinary investigation requires looking at history and political structures, as well as evaluating how the conflict comes to be: often, fear of a distant or foreign ruler, and a dissolution of what makes a nation unique. In cosmopolitan New York City, it is easy to be swept up in a bubble of liberal development, with laudable ambitions of cultural sensitivity and acceptance. However, this course of study has enabled me to engage with those who feel threatened by "a faraway king," be it Brussels, New York City, or Washington, D.C.\n\n
        \tMy mother raised me with a lot of the lessons she herself grew up with from her father: a Cherokee man who spent most of his life in Cherokee Nation. My grandfather also had a strong influence on me growing up. Often, lessons I would learn in Christian church as a child would be supplemented with stories about my ancestry. I would hear about the land that my family has inhabited for hundreds of years, from Arkansas to Oklahoma, and learn about specific relatives, their stories, and how their stories related to not only my life, but my grandfather\'s life, as well as my mother\'s. This manner of viewing oneself as a piece of a larger, spiritual ancestry impacted me in the manner I approach the world, particularly as I engage with relationships with individuals, God, land, and even New York City.\n\n
        \tAs I started my higher education in the City, I was keenly aware of the incompatibility between the knowledge imparted onto me by my ancestry and the educational system at NYU. I have developed, like many people with indigenous ancestry, a dual-perspective, what could be described as two brains or "double consciousness". My mother often says that she is "half-in" and "half-out" of her spiritual awareness, only acknowledging and interacting with Cherokee consciousness part of the time, able to completely push out imbedded cultural understandings in order to function and thrive in American society. For her, that includes trivial aspects of living, like the cliched "Indian time," where the number on the clock does not have any correlation to a necessity to be any place. It also involves more significant ways of interacting with the world; meandering stories "should" be cut short for the sake of time; facts should be presented outright; the prioritizing of data over experiences. \n\n
        \t But why? Why are indigenous ideas banned to the history books, outdated? And moreover, what can be done to reverse the genocide, of bodies and beliefs? As I\'ve considered these questions, I\'ve found myself peripherally engaging with Julia Parker, a Coast Miwok-Kashaya Pomo basket weaver. Parker is one of the most prominent indigenous basket weavers in the world, with her baskets featured in a variety of museums around the world. Parker often spoke about her time in boarding school, where children were completely immersed in the European-American culture, in language, appearance, and experience. This was in the pursuit of "civilizing the savages," and this mentality lingers today, as society tends to view indigenous people as artifacts rather than relevant living beings today. The effects of the Indian Schools are still felt in such severe cultural disintegration amongst indigenous groups.\n\n
        \tIn New York state, one of the most prominent Indian Schools was the Thomas Asylum for Orphan and Destitute Indian Children, which operated from 1855 to 1957. It was located in the Cattaraugus Indian Reservation and considered progressive for the time because had five Native American members on its board of trustees. It\'s mission, however, was the same: "civilizing." This brings into question a great deal about the role of educated youth, particularly what education can look like, and should look like. The question develops further as we acknowledge the problematic nature of these schools and attempt to reach reconciliation.\n\n
        \tPaulette Regan is the Director of Research for the Truth and Reconciliation Commission of Canada. The Canadian government established this commission in order to come to an understanding and healing between communities. Regan wrote Unsettling the Settler Within as an argument for the possibilities of decolonization. Decolonization, in this context, is transforming the manner we approach moving forward, from one of making excuses for the time period in which the violence occurred, to engaging with respect and honesty. Regan speaks about the belief that non-indigenous Canadians "know what is best for Indigenous people" (4). Reconciliation and embracing new knowledge moves beyond apologies for abuses that happened in indian schools, but extends to reconsidering history in a manner that addresses the root of the problem: colonialism. \n\n
        \tThis project has included looking into my own background with acknowledging my ancestry related to indigeneity, as well as to colonial powers. This has been academic in my concentration, but also in my personal investigation of what it means to be educated. In researching more about indian schools and the future of indigenous youth carrying knowledge, the importance of indigenous community has become even more evident. I hope that my personal experience in beginning to unpack what this means can help spur dialogue about indigenous youth, and their experience, today.


    </string>

</resources>
